<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id></id><title>Sai's blog</title><subtitle>I do data visualizations, reverse engineering, mathematics of all kinds and also write!</subtitle> <updated>2021-01-24T15:42:40+11:00</updated> <author> <name>Sai Kumar Murali Krishnan</name> <uri></uri> </author><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 Sai Kumar Murali Krishnan </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>VoltChip</title><link href="/posts/voltchip/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VoltChip" /><published>2021-01-24T00:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-01-24T00:00:00+11:00</updated> <id>/posts/voltchip/</id> <content src="/posts/voltchip/" /> <author> <name>Sai Kumar Murali Krishnan</name> </author> <category term="C" /> <summary> A simple Chip-8 emulator ported to WASM VoltChip is a simple demonstration of the potential of deploying to WebAssembly, which allows for binary execution of code via webpages. While emulating Chip-8, an interpreted language with 35 opcodes is not unique, implementing the logic and finding that the code works relatively well with minor adjustments shows that the implementation could be upscale... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Combining WebAssembly and Emulation</title><link href="/posts/emulation-and-webassembly/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Combining WebAssembly and Emulation" /><published>2021-01-24T00:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-01-24T00:00:00+11:00</updated> <id>/posts/emulation-and-webassembly/</id> <content src="/posts/emulation-and-webassembly/" /> <author> <name>Sai Kumar Murali Krishnan</name> </author> <category term="C" /> <summary> WebAssembly and Emulation - Chip 8 Introduction WebAssembly In recent times, deploying compiled languages such as C, Rust and other languages to web pages has been made possible due to WebAssembly. The technology allows for compiled code on a webpage without much code in JavaScript, which this tutorial intends to go through. In my testing, Emscripten was awkward to set up due to the variety o... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>SETools</title><link href="/posts/setools/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SETools" /><published>2021-01-09T00:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-01-09T00:00:00+11:00</updated> <id>/posts/setools/</id> <content src="/posts/setools/" /> <author> <name>Sai Kumar Murali Krishnan</name> </author> <category term="Python" /> <category term="Webapp" /> <summary> A way to summarize dull and hard to visualize unit data SETools is a data visualization web application that takes in unit data and student satisfaction to create a colorful visualization of how well received a unit is. The libraries involved include Dash, Plotly and Pandas. The use of Dash circumvented the need to use a language such as javascript for a frontend and provided powerful interact... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>uwucode</title><link href="/posts/uwucode/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="uwucode" /><published>2021-01-08T00:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-01-08T00:00:00+11:00</updated> <id>/posts/uwucode/</id> <content src="/posts/uwucode/" /> <author> <name>Sai Kumar Murali Krishnan</name> </author> <category term="Rust" /> <summary> An esoteric toy programming language uwucode is an interpreted programming languaged coded in Rust and boasts ridiculous keywords that derive from recent pop-culture. While the language itself may be satirical and impractical to use, it conveys simple aspects of language design in a beginner friendly manner, something of interest to a variety of programmers. I will eventually do a write-up on ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Mathematica and the potential gaming of VCE</title><link href="/posts/gaming_vce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mathematica and the potential gaming of VCE" /><published>2021-01-08T00:00:00+11:00</published> <updated>2021-01-09T16:28:54+11:00</updated> <id>/posts/gaming_vce/</id> <content src="/posts/gaming_vce/" /> <author> <name>Sai Kumar Murali Krishnan</name> </author> <category term="Wolfram Mathematica" /> <summary> Background Following my high school graduation, Marty Ross and I had worked on an article discussing the application of Mathematica in the context of high school mathematics and how programming can subvert mathematics testing. After a relentless flurry of corrections, addendums, errata and other edits, the paper was finally published to the Vinculum, a mathematics journal targeted at secondary... </summary> </entry> </feed>
